Yale just hosted Kimberly Crenshaw, the professor who coined the term intersectionality, as
well as other renowned professors to discuss the AP African American Studies Band in Florida
and the subsequent curriculum changes made by College Board.
Here are five huge takeaways.
Number one, DeCenter DeSantis.
A lot of justified outrage to these events focuses on Florida Governor Ron DeSantis.
But treating this problem as a product of one man's actions ignores years of conservative
organizing around these education attacks.
Also, it might let off the hook powerful education leaders like university presidents
who have failed to take a stand.
Two, media coverage has been irresponsible.
News headlines, even from reputable sources, have been really downplaying the seriousness
of this issue.
For example, Professor Crenshaw read off a New York Times headline that says, DeSantis takes
on the education establishment and builds his brand.
She then suggested headlines that would be much more appropriate, like, Black Studies
is the next venue in the war against academic freedom.
Three, College Board's defense is weak.
So College Board claims that the curriculum changes were not due to political pressure
because they happened before the Florida ban.
But many have pointed out that the same talking points that Ron DeSantis used were echoed by
conservatives and conservative newspapers going way back into 2022.
But regardless of what prompted these changes, College Board is not absolved from the damaging
impact of them.
Many works from Black thinkers that were taken out of their curriculum have been so impactful
in shaping world events that to just call them secondary sources within African American
Studies would be ahistorical.
On top of this, it would be a huge double standard to force students to learn the works of white
theorists in classes like AP US History, but forbid them from learning the works of Black
theorists in AP African American Studies.
One professor said that if we have to learn James Madison's ideas on democracy, then it's
equally important to learn Angela Davis' ideas on abolitionist democracy.
Four, this AP ban is just the beginning.
Fascist governments all over the world often start their agenda by censoring counter-narratives.
And it's clear that the narrative that they want to push is one that ignores racial injustice
by pretending that the horrors of American history have no impact on today.
In the words of Professor Stanley, they are trying to make inexplicable Black movements for
social justice.
They're trying to make it so that when you see a protest, you're like, what are they complaining
about?
And Professor Ferguson said that this attack is just starting with race, but it's really
an attack on all critical pedagogy, all critical thinking, and all critical literacy, and it
should alarm everyone.
And five, we need to mobilize.
This issue is not going away soon, and we all need to act to confront it, especially to
protect public schools for both teachers and students.
There's going to be a webinar about what's going on and what needs to happen, and the link
will be in my caption.
I'll end with a profound quote from Professor Crenshaw that I want everyone to remember.
The world around us is not just the way things are, it's the way things have been made to
be.
And yes, we can do something about it.
Did you attend the event or watch the live stream?
If so, I know you probably have notes.
Please leave anything I missed in the comments and follow for more.